Guide to the Randi Ward collection, 2012-2014.
Ward, Randi collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Randi Ward collection, 2012-Present
8493
Ward, Randi
.2 cubic feet
Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Publications featuring translations from Faroese and Icelandic by Randi Ward.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Randi Ward is a writer, translator and photographer from West Virginia.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications featuring translations from Faroese and Icelandic and photography by Randi Ward. Also several CDs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ward, Randi
Subjects:
Faroese language; Faroese poetry; Icelandic poetry
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Beloit Poetry Journal Vol. 63 No.1, Fall 2012 (Box 1)
  Contains K. A. Hays, Liz Kay, Hannah K. galvin, Matthew Nienow, Jaydn DeWald, Richard Foerster, Ephraim Scott Sommers, Michael Bazzett, Randi Ward, Caitlin Dwyer, Lucy Anderton, Brendan Constantine, Greg Wrenn, Hadara Bar-Nadav, Roger Mitchell, Jeremy Bass, Stephen O’Connor, Allison Hutchcraft, Joel Peckham, Jeremy Glazier, Philip Metres
- Cold Mountain Review Vol. 41 No. 1, Fall 2012 (Box 1)
  Contains Erin Pushman, Sonya Lea, Ian Burkett, Rebecca Lauren, Hank Hudepohl, Chris Souza, William Palmer, Laura Paul Watson, Lisa Hammond, Heather Holliger, Catherine Tahmin, Bernadette Geyer, Alyse Bensel, Karen J. Weyant, Bill Brown, Elias Simpson, Sabrina Ito, Mike McGeehon, Z.G. Tomaszewski, Shivani Mehta, Terry Ann Thaxton, Elizabeth Hoover, Marsha Truman Cooper, Charlie Bondhus, Elizabeth Genovise, Julian Huffman, Randi Ward
- The Bitter Oleander: A Magazine of Contemporary International Poetry and Short Fiction Vol. 19 No. 1, Spring 2013 (Box 1)
- Cimarron Review 185, Fall 2013 (Box 1)
  Contains William Olsen, Beth Marzoni, Vanessa Stauffer, Rebecca Lehmann, Holly Day, Lisa Furmanski, Francesc Parcerisas, Christine Steward-Nuñez, Sara E. Lamers, John McCullough, Daniel Saalfeld, Malcolm Guite, Hilary Vaughn Dobel, CJ Evans, Alyson Hagy, Andrew Ellis Bates, Kate Woodworth, Richard M. Lange
- Fjords: Arts and Literary Review Vol. 2 Issue 2, Fall/Winter 2013 (Box 1)
  Contains John McKernan, Ashley-Elizabeth Best, Christian Anton Gerard, George Moore, Yumi Sakugawa, Jacob M. Appel, Dan O’Brien, Sean Carswell, Robert Mengert, Paul David Adkins, Guðrið Helmsdal, Randi Ward, Tóriddyr Poulsen, Randi Ward, Seth Clabough, Robin Richardson, Christina Francine, Kayti Doolittle
- Arcadia 8, 2014 (Box 1)
  Contains Joe Scott, Ilya Lyashevsky, Paul Catalano, Laura Birdsall, Harold Whit Williams, Carol Hamilton, John Palen, Laura E. Miller, Abbie J. Leavens, Peggy Aylsworth, Hannah Fischer, Edgar Kunz, Danielle Luther Luebbe, Joelle Schumacher
- Skidrow Penthouse #16, 2014 (Box 1)
- Scandinavian Review Celebrating 100 Years of the Scandinavian Review, Spring 2014 (Box 1)
- Beloit Poetry Journal Vol. 64 No.4, Summer 2014 (Box 1)
  Contains Peter Leight, Liz Robbins, Daniel Bourne, Karl Plank, Claire Åkebrand, Tóroddur Poulsen, Laura McCullough, Jeff Ewing, Lauren Camp, Matt Salyer, Chera Hammons, Craig Finlay, Jessica Jacobs, Michael Broek
- Beyond the Grey by Gudrid Hansdóttir, 2011; CD-2173 (Box 1)
- Dýrð Í dauðaþögn by Ásgeir Trausti, 2012; CD-2174 (Box 1)
- Stjørnudust úr føroyskum yrkíngum í 200 ár, 2011 (Box 1)
  Four volume anthology. Accompanied by Kestrel (Department of Language and Literature, Fairmont State University) postcard from Randi Ward featuring poem "Shade" from Kestrel issue 32. Anthology contains poem "Grannsíggin" by Ward (Faroese name: Randi á Ryggi) on p. 124-125 of Volume I. Volume I also contains Símun av Skarði, Jóhanna Maria Skylv Hansen, Gudmundur Bruun, Bjørgfinnur Nielsen, Kári P, Katrin Reinert, Bergur Rønne Moberg, Jóannes Dalsgaard, Regin Dahl, Jóan Petur uppi í Trøð, Mina Reinert, Rasmus Effersøe, Hans Dávur Matras, Andrias Ziska, Oskar Hermannsson, Kim Simonsen, Gunnar Hoydal, Janus Djurhuus, Andrea í Norðradali, Poul Klein, Hans Andrias Djurhuus, Billa Hansen, Tummas N. Djurhuus, Hans J. Glerfoss, Malan Poulsen, Carl Jóhan Jensen, Marna Glerfoss á Kamarinum, Anna Mattsson, Jens Hendrik Djurhuus, Mina Reinert, Jacobsen Gata, Sigri M. Gaini, Louis Zachariassen, Martin Næs, Nólsoyar-Páll, Hans Dávur Matras, Jørgen Hammershaimb, Tóroddur Poulsen, Alexandur Weihe, Sólmundur Joensen, Nólsoyar-Páll, Jóhanna Maria Skylv Hansen, Jóannes Patursson, Tróndur Olsen, Hjalmar Hammershaimb, M. A. Jacobsen, Rannvá Skeel Johannesen, Katrin Reinert, Nancy Vesturbú, Jóanes Nielsen, Hans Dalsgaard, Sólrún Michelsen, Rasmus Rasmussen, Oddfíður M. Rasmussen, Jnley á Løgmansbø, Ebba Henze, Sólrún Michelsen, Nancy Vesturbú, Martin Næs, Sjóvarbóndin, Esmar Jacobsen Gata, Anna Sofía á Rípuni, Bernhard Brim, Hans J. Glerfoss, Jákup Berg, Bjørgfinnur Nielsen, Rasmus Effersøe, Arnbjørn Ólavsson Dalsgarð, Arnbjørn Danielsen, Símun Mikal Zachariassen, Louis Zachariassen, Óðin Ódn, Karsten Hoydal, Dunganon, Dánial Hoydal, Heðin M. Klein, S. P. Zachariassen, Axel Tórgarð, M. S. Viðstein, Bernhard Brim, Hjalmar Hammershaimb, Kvívíks-Jógvan, Hans Daalsgard, Petur Jensen, Fríðrikur Peterson, Ólavur Uti í Stovuni, Heðin M. Klein, Marjun Syderbø Kjelnæs, Rikard Long, Tóroddur Poulsen, Jónley á løgmansbø, Vida Akselsdóttir Højgaard, Olivar á Ryggi, Agnar Artúvertin, Mikkjal á Ryggi, Ólavur Michelsen, Martin Joensen, Rói Patursson, Hanus Kamban, Valdemar á Løgmansbø, Kim Simonsen, Sigurð Joensen, Sonja Schneider, Pól F Joensen, Oskar Hermannsson, Oddfriður M. Rasmussen, Jóannes Dalsgaard, Tróondur Olsen, Jógvan Nolsø, Hanus Debes Joensen, Martin Joensen, Tummas N. Djurhuus, Glerfoss á Kamarinum, Arnbjørn Ólavsson Dalsgarð, Hanus Kamban, Anna Mattsson, Valdemar á Løgmansbø, Christian Matras, Rói Patursson, Agnar Artúvertin, Jóanes Nielsen, Olivar á Ryggi, Gunnar Hoydal, Poul Klein, Bergur Rønne Moberg, Símun an Skarði, M. A. Jacobsen, Astrid Joensen, Guðrið Helmsdal, Símun Mikal Zachariassen, Fríðrikur Peterson, Jakob Jakoben, Alexandur Kristiansen, Hjørdis Djurhuss, Vida Akselsdóttir Hjøgaard, William Heinesen, Steinbjørn B. Jacobsen, Jøorgen Hammershaimb, Regin Dahl, Elsa í Nýggjustovu, Heðin Brú, Guðrið Helmsdal, Gudmundur Bruun, M. S. Viðstein, Jákup Dahl, Maria Eide Petersen, William Heinesen, Andrias Ziska, Nyholm Debess, Astrid Poulsen, Rikard Long, and Marjun Syderbø Kjelnæs.
  Volume II contains Stev, Rói Patursson, Regin Dahl, Bernhard Brim, Astrid Pálsson, Guðrið Helmsdal, Pól F Joensen, Martin Joensen, Gandaørindi, Hans J. Glerfoss, Hans Andrias Djurhuus, Sigri M. Gaini, Kvæðabrot, Tummas N. Djurhuus, Hjørdis Djurhuus, Bernhard Brim, Sigri M. Gaini, Rikard Long, Jóan Christian Poulsen, Alexandur Kristiansen, Gunnar Hoydal, Carl Jóhan Jensen, Christian Matras, Malan Poulsen, Tóroddur Poulsen, Kristin í Geil, Heðin M. Klein, Karsten Hoydal, Símun an Skarði, Danisspæl, Martin Joensen, and Karsten Hoydal.
  Volume III contains Sigurð Joensen, Heðin M. Klein, Regin Dahl, Elsa í Nýggjustovu, Malan Poulsen, Sigurð Joensen, Rói Patursson. Astrid Joensen, Esmar Jacobsen Gata, Janus Djurhuus, Símun av Skarði, Guðrið Helmsdal, Jákup Hansen, Sigga Due Sørensen, Christian Matras, Jóhanna Maria Skylv Hansen, Hanus Debes Joensen, Karsten Hoydal, Hans Andrias Djurhuus, Kristian Osvald Viderø, Halgikvæði, Poul F. Joensen, and Astrid Joensen.
  Volume IV contains Mikkjal á Ryggi, Steinbjørn B. Jacobsen, Hans Andrias Djurhuus, Oskar Hermannsson, Andrias í Norðradali, Chr. Matras, J, Bernhard Brim, Símun av Skarði, and Sigurð Joensen.
- Bridges by Eivør, 2015; CD-2175 (Box 1)
  Lyrics for "Tides" written by Randi Ward.
- Mantis A Journal of Poetry, Criticism, and Translation, Issue 13, 2015 (Box 1)
  Randi Ward contributes "On December Morning" pg. 76-77. Also contains Joe Betz, Natalie Shapero, Doug Ramspeck, Aaron Anstett, H. L. Hix, Keith Taylor, Meredith Davies Hadaway, C. W. Emerson, Stephen Massimilla, MJ Bender, Will Harris, Patrick Ryan Frank, Joe Delong, Alec Hershman, Emily Tuszynska, Benjamin S. Grossberg, Patricia Gray, Randall Brown, Monica Berlin, Matthew Stark, Jóhan Martin Christiansen, Kim Simonsen, Karen van Dyck, Eleanor Goodman, Ravi Shankar, Ha Poong Kim, Brett Foster, Michael Goldman, Darla Himeles, Robyn Newkumet, Fiona Sze-Lorrain, David Roderick, Kimberly Johnson, Jeffrey Skinner, Bruce Lack, and Zeeshan Sahil.
- Lux Vol. I, 2013 (Box 1)
  Randi Ward contributes photos "PTSD" (pg. 24) and "Sycamore" (pg. 25). Also contains Gregory Robinson, David Emerson, Rick Moody, Roberta Borger, Derek Williams, Michelle Boyd, Erica Meiners, Celia Bland, Dianne Kornberg, Ram Devineni, Bianca Stone, Rachel James, David Prescott-Steed, Ken Cormier, Richard MacDonald, and Tim Kahl.
- Lux Vol. II, 2014 (Box 1)
  Randi Ward contributes the photo "Lights Out" pg. 28. Also includes Chris George, Troy Jollimore, Andrew Keating, Jessica Hagy, Nick Flynn, Sarah Sentilles, Brandon Friend, Jason Griffin, Carne Griffiths, Courtney Hickerson, Mac Premo, Adrianna Dufay, Celia Bland, Dianne Kornberg, Giselle Potter, Courtney Hickerson, Donna Emerson, Matthew Cusick, Aaron McFavis, Jon Woowdward,
- small po[r]tions Issue 4, 2015 (Box 1)
  Randi Ward contributes photos "Meyegraine 51" (pg. 16) and "Meyegraine 65" (pg. 17). Also contains Colin Post, Josh Fomon, Nico Vassilakis, Theodore Worozbyt, Jennifer Arcuni, Jessica Cogar, Derek Pollard, Michael Flatt, Dylan W. Krieger, Ivan Faute, Kevin McLellan, Matt Trease, Valerie Wernet, Aeron Bergman, Alejandra Salinas, Jill Magi, Dennis Caswell, Wailana Kalama, Lora Straub, Philip Kobylarz, Jeremy Schmidt, and Genevieve Kaplan.
- The Sonder Review Issue 2, 2015 (Box 1)
  Randi Ward contributes photos "Meyegraine" pg. 24 and pg. 34. Also contains Jessemy Neiger, Lynn Holmgren, Kayla Pongrac, Tim Kahl, Jane Williams, Lisa Taylor, Barbara Harroun, Nina Alvarez, Amy Feltman, Rohan Garg, Brian Barbeito, Alli Hurley, Adel Souto, Kristen Oberly, and Andi Tomassi.
- South Loop Review Fiction and Art, the Final Issue, 2015 (Box 1)
  Randi Ward contributes photo and description "In the Belly of the Bjørn" pg. 77. Also contains Allen Gee, Christopher Malcomb, Jad Atkins, Allie Rowbottom, Rebecca Huntman, Marcia Aldrich, J. David Stevens, Amy Bernhard, Sarah Minor, Kaori Fujimoto, Joey Franklin, Cory Brown, Cora Jacobs, Andrea Mele, Jonathan Mack, Adam Clayton-Holland, Karen Fisher, Austin Ream, Stephanie Jurusz, Susannah B. Mintz, Timothy Fernandez, Jeffrey S. Chapman, Tyler Gasek, Kristy Ramsey, Joris Soeding, Cora Jacobs, and Brian Ritchard.
- Vencil tíðarrit fyri skaldskap á føroyskum, nr. 15/2015, 8. árg., 2015 (Box 1)
  Randi Ward contributes “Seks yrkingar”: “Froskur,” “Á snórinum,” “Snarljós,” “Bað,” “Slóttur,” “Uppringing” (Óla Jákup Niclasen týddi) pg. 46-48.
- Sigmunds kvæði yngra (Randi Ward skipar): 1 CD-ROM, December 2005 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous correspondence from Randi Ward to Curator, Fiske Icelandic Collection, 2015 (Box 1)
  Notes dated 01 September and 27 October 2015; holiday card for 2015.